Every fairy tale ends.
Spencer is a drama, history film directed by Pablo Larraín.
During her Christmas holidays with the royal family at the Sandringham estate in
Norfolk, England, Diana decides to leave her marriage to Prince Charles.
Diana, played by Kristen Stewart.
Major Alistair Gregorys, played by Timothy Spall.
William, played by Jack Nielen.
Harry, played by Freddie Spry.
Charles, played by Jack Farthing.
Darren, played by Sean Harris.
Spencer is a 2021 historical psychological drama film directed
by Pablo Larraín and written by Steven Knight.
The film is about Diana, Princess of Wales's existential crisis during the Christmas of 1991,
as she considers divorcing Prince Charles and leaving the British royal family.
Kristen Stewart and Jack Farthing star as Diana and Charles respectively, along with Jack
Neilen and Freddie Spry as Prince William and Prince Harry, respectively.
Also starring Timothy Spall, Sean Harris, and Sally Hawkins.
It is the second film in Larraín's trilogy of iconic 20th century
women, succeeding Jackie (2016) and preceding Maria (2024).
Spencer premiered at the 78th Venice International Film Festival on 3 September 2021, and was
theatrically released in the United Kingdom and the United States on 5 November 2021.
The film grossed $25.2 million worldwide on an $18 million budget.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, with
Stewart's performance garnering widespread praise.
For her performance as Diana, Stewart was nominated for the Academy Award for Best
Actress, as well as a Golden Globe Award and a Critics' Choice Movie Award.
The film explores themes of princess, marriage crisis,
royal family, biography, based on true story.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.